Liam Li 021-08829682

Full Stack Software Engineer

limeng0427@gmail.com

Summary

Certified AWS associate Solutions Architect, Developer.

Qualified and experienced full stack developer with local and overseas working experience. I am well-versed in developing web application, embedded system, web service from working experience and studying and I am experienced software development, debugging and testing. I have expertise in data structure, algorithms and data analysis which are also recognized by the former employers.

Skills

IT Skills Back-end Skills: .NET MVC, .Net Core, C#, C, C++, SQL Server, MongoDB,

Report/Email Service, RESTful Web Service/API, WCF, WPF, LINQ, EF

Front-end Skills: JavaScript(jQuery, Angular, TypeScript), HTML, CSS, Bower, Bootstrap Embedded System Skills: Assembly and Linux from work experience and studying

Others: AWS, Linux, Data Analyses Skills using Weka and R

Project Skills Agile, Scrum, SDLC and Change Management, Source Control (Git, SVN)
Telecommunication Skills Telecommunications principle and different generations of technologies

Installation, maintenance and trouble-shooting of telecommunications equipment,

Customers Service Skills Empathy, patience and consistency; adaptability; sense of humor

Education

Postgraduate Diploma July 2016 – July 2017 PGD in Computing

Department of Computing United Institute of Technology

Web Application Development, Agile & Lean Software Delivery, Network Programming,
Data Mining and Industry Applications, Machine Learning and Information Processing
September 2011 - July 2014 Control Theory & Control Engineering

School of Information Engineering Nanchang University

C++ Programming, Principles of GPS and Application, Computer Controlling System, Design of Embedded System, Sensor Technology & Application, Advanced Mathematics

Work Experience

Master of Science

◆ THL Digital / Togo Group

Software Developer

December 2019 – Now Auckland, New Zealand

Responsibilities:

Developing Web API service, Mongo Realm app, report service and multi device management apps

Projects: Campervan inventory management system

Campervan telemactics system

IoT multi device management system

Technologies: C#, .Net Core, JavaScript, MongoDb, Mongo Realm, elastic search, git, Jira, web service, Xamarin.

◆ Trackit Limited Software Developer

April 2017 – May 2019 Auckland, New Zealand

Responsibilities:

Software Development: Developing new web application features, services and Web API

Updating Database items and their relative data operation code

Testing new features and existing features/ changes.

Project Management: Product release, Project workflow tracking with Jira.

Maintenance & Support: Existing project's issues fixing and performance improving

Dealing with team members and customers' technical issues.

Projects: Subscription Package & Feature Management

Checklist & Driver Behavior Management Reporting Service, Car Pooling System

NZTA Vehicle Profile Processing Service, Asset Maintenance & Management Logistic Consignment Solution: Customized Job/ Docket Processor & Viewer

Technologies: C#, .Net 4, Generics, WPF, SQL Server, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, SVN, JIRA, Web Service/ API, WCF, Report Service, WebPack, Exceptions Management, Async and multi-threaded applications, GPS.

◆ Ed.Collective

Database Developer, Contract

January 2017 - March 2017

Auckland, New Zealand

Responsibilities: As the independent developer and data analyst of Ed.Collective data review project. I'm in charge of the technical design and working as SQL Server database developer to implement this project. I am pushing the data storage method shifting from Access to SQL Server along with data analyses project and making future working process more efficient to operate with standard coding and infrastructures including UDF, stored procedure and data import & process T-SQL script.

Projects: Data Population Project

Technologies: SQL Server, T-SQL, Stored Procedure, Dynamic SQL, SSMS

◆ ZTE Global Telecommunication Corporation

Software Developer

July 2014 - June 2015

Beijing, China

Responsibilities: Business Analyses for Automatic Switch Optical network software system; software development and unit test matching new features; system issues tracking and processing; development of command line code for site engineer; system debug with testers and developers from different sections of the system.

Projects: Wavelength Division Multiplexing Automatic Switch Optical Network for Intelligent OTN **Technologies**: Embedded System, C/C++ language, Java, Scrum Development, Unit Test, Integration Test

Nanchang University

Project Manager

June2012 - May 2014

Nanchang, Jiangxi, China

Responsibilities: Software system design, development and testing; on site telecommunication cable and fiber wiring, fiber fusion, network environment build and configuration, plan and schedule making of project implementation; business analyses with information collected from factory manager; technical feasibility check; training courses delivery for new staffs or system users.

Projects: Silkworm Egg Incubation Monitoring System

Hospital miniature laboratory information management system (LIS)

Andon System for Automobile Workshop & Remote Energy Monitoring System

Lincomycin Fermentation Process Parameters Monitoring System

Manufacturing Information System (A4 Production Line)

Maintenance and Upgrade for Temperature Control System of Large Trolley Resistance Furnace

Technologies: SQL Server DB, Delphi, Site Management, CRM, ERP

Interests

In my spare time, I volunteer in events and catch up friends by great walk, scuba diving, marathon, road trips.

Reference

Available on request.

More detailed information can be found on LinkedIn: https://nz.linkedin.com/in/liamli2014